

Christopher Taylor Gonzalez Rivera FULL STACK DEVELOPER

With a Master's degree in Computer Science and a background in Electronics Engineering, I have amassed over five years of experience as a Full Stack Developer, specializing in MERN technologies (MongoDB, Express JS, React, NodeJS). My journey in the technology field has been not just a professional trajectory but also a deep passion for innovating and solving complex problems.

taylorgr@outlook.com

- +52 33 3172 8350
- https://taylorgr93.com
- Zapopan, Jalisco, Mexico.

ACADEMIC TRAINING

Master's degree in Computer Science at Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, 2020 - 2022

Electronic engineering at Centro de Enseñanza Tecnica Industrial (CETI), 2012 - 2016

SKILLS & FRAMEWORKS

JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, React
MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS
Docker, Docker Compose
Yarn, NPM Axios, Fetch, JWT,
ApiGateway, Git
React Hooks, Redux, Zustand, JEST,
Context API, Webpack, Next JS
Material UI, Tailwind CSS
Scrum, JIRA, Monday
HTML, CSS, C#, Python, C++
SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL
RESTful APIs, JSON, XML
AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS Lambda
Gitlab CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

GRUPO ABSA / KNESYS PLUS, April 2019 - Today

Development of applications for industry 4.0 and IoT, allowing users to monitor variables in real time and extract valuable information for making intelligent decisions. In addition, we develop customized web solutions adapted to the needs of our clients.

- The AWS services I have used are EC2, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch.
- Container handling with Docker and Docker Compose.
- For unit testing in JavaScript I have used libraries such as Mocha and Chai, and for React I have used JEST and React Testing Library.
- I have developed a wide set of REST APIs for multiple projects, ranging from personnel management systems to e-commerce platforms.
- Knowledge of the Linux command line, task and script running, system administration, and configuration (Network, Encryption File System).
- CI/CD using GitLab CI to automate application deployment.
- Experience developing REST Full API services for the seamless integration of GPS location services and Motorola RF communication services.

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

JABIL, November 2018 - April 2019

Automate processes, through the development of innovative and efficient web applications. Provide technical support to the manufacturing area.

- Development dynamic web applications for product validation (ASP.Net Core Framework, HTML, JavaScript, CSS).
- Responsible for updating and continuously maintaining existing PHP applications (PHP, phpMyAdmin).
- Manipulation and processing of data in XML format, implementing code script in PHP.
- Implement and manage the open source OsTicket application, to improve ticket generation and technical support management.

OTHERS SKILLS & TOOLS

Visual Studio Code, Postman
MongoDB Compass, Virtual Box
SQL Managment Studio
MySQL Workbench
WordPress, Figma, Ngrok
phpMyAdmin

SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork, Communication,
Work ethic, Self-motivation
Compromise, Creativity,
Problem solving, Continuos lerning
Empathy, Sense of Responsibility

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUPPORT ENGINEER

POUNCE CONSULTING, August 2016 - November 2018

Development of applications for the validation and verification of the operation of the products manufactured by the company, as well as the improvement of processes.

- Development of Applications and graphical user interfaces with Windows Form with .NET and C# for validation of electronic meters.
- Database design and management (SQL server, MySQL).
- Generation of csv reports from the sql management studio tool using specific queries.
- Customer service (had to travel throughout the Mexican Republic to support the company's manufacturing plants).
- I have knowledge of production lines for electronic manufacturing.

DIAGNOSTIC TECHNICIAN

JABIL, January 2016 - November 2016

- Analyze and diagnose electrical failures occurred in the electronic cards (PCB's).
- Report failures in the process, operating errors and test equipment failures to my immediate boss.
- Maintain the diagnostic efficiency established in the project.
- Maintain 100% of the certifications required by the company and the project.
- Use of electronic measurement equipment (multimeter, oscilloscope, spectrum analyzer).